[{"C": "Morse code by an old-fashioned telegraph key.", "answer": "E", "question": "\u201cClick and Bang\u201d is the name commonly given to:", "status": "ok", "A": "Early American cowboys that were changed to Ranchers by barbed wire.", "E": "The automatic dial exchange.", "D": "The manual telephone exchange that was the foundation of the communications revolution.", "B": "Successful talk-show host automobile repairmen."}, {"C": "amber", "answer": "C", "question": "\u201cElectron\u201d came from the Greek word for:", "status": "ok", "A": "electricity", "E": "ivory.", "D": "the color yellow", "B": "negative"}, {"C": "motion pictures", "answer": "D", "question": "A certain inventor got the nickname \u201cwizard of Menlo Park\u201d as a result of his invention of:", "status": "ok", "A": "electric light", "E": "stock ticker.", "D": "phonograph", "B": "telegraph"}, {"C": "social confusion", "answer": "A", "question": "According to Chaplin, this was at the heart of America\u2019s economic problems in the 1930\u2019s:", "status": "ok", "A": "technological unemployment - machines taking jobs.", "D": "technological decline", "B": "political unrest"}, {"C": "about to occur", "answer": "A", "question": "According to Rogers, the marriage between science and engineering is:", "status": "ok", "A": "permanent", "D": "dangerous to religion and society", "B": "shaky"}, {"C": "\u201cThere is nothing practical that can be easily characterized with theories.\u201d", "answer": "A", "question": "According to Rogers:", "status": "ok", "A": "\u201cThere is nothing more practical than a good theory.\u201d", "D": "\u201cPractical engineering makes little use of scientific theories.\u201d", "B": "\u201cThere are practically no good theories today.\u201d"}, {"C": "the early Williamsburg design", "answer": "B", "question": "According to Spiro Kostof, Catherine Beecher felt the kitchen should be modeled after:", "status": "ok", "A": "the kitchen at Monticello", "D": "the kitchen in the Hearst Castle", "B": "the cook\u2019s cabin on a steamship"}, {"C": "new scientific discoveries and a lot of new creative inventions.", "answer": "D", "question": "According to Volti, a lot of emphasis on principles and methods of science can lead to:", "status": "ok", "A": "the solving of all technical problems.", "D": "restricted creativity and overly rigid approach to solving technical problems.", "B": "no technological problems being solved."}, {"C": "invent steel for use in car frames.", "answer": "B", "question": "Albert Kahn worked with Ford to", "status": "ok", "A": "introduce electrical machines to the assembly line.", "D": "develop safety glass for cars.", "B": "design buildings whose walls were not load-bearing."}, {"C": "sphere", "answer": "B", "question": "Alexander Graham Bell patented construction using what geometric shape?", "status": "ok", "A": "cube", "D": "pyramid", "B": "tetrahedron"}, {"C": "Substantial, since 80% of the entire war production was done by converted auto assembly lines.", "answer": "D", "question": "American experience in the automobile assembly line had what effect in World War II?", "status": "ok", "A": "Very little, since it was hard to convert auto production to production of war materials.", "E": "Substantial, since 50% of the entire war production was done by converted auto assembly lines.", "D": "Substantial, since 20% of the entire war production was done by converted auto assembly lines.", "B": "Very little, since much of the auto industry had shifted its production outside of the U.S."}, {"C": "phonograph, movies, and train.", "answer": "A", "question": "Among the early signs of modernization in Japan in the late 19th century were the:", "status": "ok", "A": "rickshaw, horse-drawn trolley, and train.", "E": "education, full democracy, and women rights.", "D": "phonograph, movies, and transistor radios", "B": "phonograph, horse-drawn trolley, and train."}, {"C": "the 500th anniversary of the discovery of America", "answer": "E", "question": "An April 1993 issue of Science is devoted to:", "status": "ok", "A": "the 100th anniversary of the invention of radio", "E": "women in science.", "D": "the 90th anniversary of the invention of the airplane", "B": "racism in science."}, {"C": "Proverbs", "answer": "C", "question": "An extended treatment of the role of women in ancient Middle Eastern society can be found in:", "status": "ok", "A": "Volti\u2019s study of social groups", "D": "Philemon", "B": "Teich\u2019s study of social groups"}, {"C": "Buster Keaton", "answer": "B", "question": "Any discussion of movies and modern technology is certain to focus upon this person and the problemshe encountered as a factory worker in the film Modern Times.", "status": "ok", "A": "Mack Sennett", "D": "Frederick Taylor", "B": "Charlie Chaplin"}, {"C": "burning of wood and other plant products.", "answer": "D", "question": "Before industrialization, almost all of the energy used came from:", "status": "ok", "A": "organic sources.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "all of the above.", "B": "human and animal muscle."}, {"C": "magnavox", "answer": "C", "question": "Before it was known as the loudspeaker, it had which of the following names?", "status": "ok", "A": "telemegaphone", "D": "magnaphone", "B": "woofer"}, {"C": "The Navigator, The General", "answer": "C", "question": "Between 1924 and 1926 Buster Keaton released two films which dealt with some major examples oftechnology.They were:", "status": "ok", "A": "City Lights, New Masses", "D": "Modern Times, Gone with the Wind", "B": "Modern Times, New Masses"}, {"C": "1,000,000 soldiers", "answer": "C", "question": "By the first decade of the 20th century, Japan assembled a modern army used in a war with a single largenation. The Japanese side had about:", "status": "ok", "A": "10,000 soldiers", "E": "None of the above. No such war occurred.", "D": "10,000,000 soldiers", "B": "100,000 soldiers"}, {"C": "American aviation", "answer": "D", "question": "Charles A. Lindbergh received a lot of credit for his flight but thought that the flight should be creditedto:", "status": "ok", "A": "American industry", "E": "None of the above", "D": "All of the above", "B": "Aeronautical research"}, {"C": "School teacher.", "answer": "A", "question": "Charles Lindbergh was the son of a Minnesota:", "status": "ok", "A": "Congressman", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Policeman.", "B": "Businessman."}, {"C": "Alexander Graham Bell", "answer": "A", "question": "Clyde Barrow was one of his great admirers:", "status": "ok", "A": "Henry Ford", "E": "Orville Wright.", "D": "Douglas MacArthur", "B": "Thomas Edison"}, {"C": "1910-1919", "answer": "B", "question": "During which period did the Model T Ford come into production?", "status": "ok", "A": "1889-1899", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "1920-1929", "B": "1900-1909"}, {"C": "identify a market before beginning work on an invention.", "answer": "C", "question": "Early in his career Edison decided to:", "status": "ok", "A": "work only on those projects he loved.", "E": "work only at the General Electric Research Labs.", "D": "work on projects that mainly interested electronics hobbyists", "B": "hire a group of individual inventors and manage their work."}, {"C": "fly-by-wire systems", "answer": "A", "question": "Early magnetic recording used metallic wires as the recording media. This technology is still found in:", "status": "ok", "A": "flight data recorders", "E": "videocassette recorders", "D": "underwater navigation systems", "B": "high-speed video editing systems"}, {"C": "Tesla", "answer": "A", "question": "Edison and this person invented the light bulb at about the same time:", "status": "ok", "A": "Swan", "E": "Bessemer.", "D": "Fisher", "B": "Argand"}, {"C": "his years of work as an apprentice to Eli Whitney", "answer": "B", "question": "Edison claimed he was helped in his work by:", "status": "ok", "A": "the constant support of his first wife", "D": "the support of his physician colleague Watson.", "B": "his hearing loss"}, {"C": "motion pictures", "answer": "B", "question": "Edison had two children whose names honored which invention?", "status": "ok", "A": "electric light", "D": "phonograph", "B": "telegraph"}, {"C": "electric light", "answer": "A", "question": "Edison\u2019s first patent was for a(n):", "status": "ok", "A": "electrical vote recorder", "E": "motion pictures.", "D": "phonograph", "B": "stock ticker"}, {"C": "2,000", "answer": "B", "question": "Edison\u2019s jumbo generators were each capable of powering this quantity of 16 candlepower lamps.", "status": "ok", "A": "1,000", "D": "5,000", "B": "1,200"}, {"C": "Edison General Electric", "answer": "B", "question": "Elisha Gray\u2019s idea for a telephone was purchased by:", "status": "ok", "A": "Westinghouse", "E": "Sony", "D": "General Electric", "B": "Western Union"}, {"C": "A railroad was built connecting Tokyo and Yokohama", "answer": "C", "question": "Fifteen years after Perry\u2019s opening of Japan to the United States and other Western nations,what had occurred?", "status": "ok", "A": "A democratic constitution for Japan had been enacted.", "E": "The emperor traveled to Washington for conversations with the president.", "D": "A bridge was built connecting oil-rich Battleship Island to Japan.", "B": "Japan invaded the Philippines and successfully pushed out the Spanish."}, {"C": "Who Cares", "answer": "D", "question": "Following the defeat of the Shogun's Army, Tokyo was designated the new capital. The word meant:", "status": "ok", "A": "New Way", "E": "Northern Capital.", "D": "Eastern Capital", "B": "New Capital"}, {"C": "He mistrusted the Blacks (African Americans) but instituted incentives to employ the Japanese.", "answer": "B", "question": "Ford had this social view:", "status": "ok", "A": "He mistrusted the Blacks (African Americans) but instituted incentives to employ the Jews.", "E": "He mistrusted the Japanese but instituted incentives to employ the Chinese.", "D": "He mistrusted the Japanese but instituted incentives to employ the Jews.", "B": "He mistrusted the Jews but instituted incentives to employ the Blacks (African Americans)."}, {"C": "breakdown movements into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary work.", "answer": "A", "question": "Frank and Lillian Gilbreth\u2019s contribution was to", "status": "ok", "A": "breakdown work into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary movements.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "breakdown work into basic traditional and rotational motions.", "B": "breakdown motion into basic movements and to eliminate unnecessary motion."}, {"C": "the formalized industrial research laboratory", "answer": "C", "question": "George Eastman and C.E. Kenneth Mees created what in 1912?", "status": "ok", "A": "the formalized manufacturing system", "D": "a school of camera lens design", "B": "a centralized photo development system"}, {"C": "Henry Ford", "answer": "E", "question": "He believed that \u201cAll possible brain work should be removed from the shop and centered in the planningorlaying-out department.\u201d", "status": "ok", "A": "Karl Benz", "E": "Frederick Taylor", "D": "William C. Durant", "B": "J. Frank Duryea"}, {"C": "Eli Whitney", "answer": "A", "question": "He called the farmer God\u2019s finest creation:", "status": "ok", "A": "Jefferson", "E": "Andrew Jackson", "D": "McCormick", "B": "Lincoln"}, {"C": "G. B. Shaw", "answer": "B", "question": "He designed the \u201cVisible Speech\u201d system used to help the deaf to speak:", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "E": "Samuel Langley", "D": "S. F. B. Morse", "B": "Melville Bell"}, {"C": "Charles Taylor", "answer": "C", "question": "He designed the engine for the Wright brothers' first airplane.", "status": "ok", "A": "Karl Benz", "E": "Frederick Taylor", "D": "William C. Durant", "B": "J. Frank Duryea"}, {"C": "O. Wright", "answer": "E", "question": "He had a major government contract to developed an airplane:", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "E": "Samuel Langley.", "D": "W. Wright", "B": "Melville Bell"}, {"C": "Poulsen", "answer": "D", "question": "He is famous for subdividing assembly of his product into simple repetitive tasks:", "status": "ok", "A": "Albert Kahn", "E": "Eli Whitney", "D": "Ford", "B": "Carnegie"}, {"C": "Alexander Graham Bell", "answer": "A", "question": "He was narrowly defeated when he ran for a seat in the U.S. Senate and was a leading candidate for U.S.President in public-opinion polls for several years:", "status": "ok", "A": "Henry Ford", "E": "Orville Wright.", "D": "Douglas MacArthur", "B": "Thomas Edison"}, {"C": "frequency-hopping signals", "answer": "C", "question": "Hedy Lamarr was involved with the invention of:", "status": "ok", "A": "FM radio", "E": "both B and D above.", "D": "facsimile machines", "B": "television"}, {"C": "G. B. Shaw", "answer": "A", "question": "Hellen Keller dedicated her autobiography to:", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "E": "Samuel Langley", "D": "S. F. B. Morse", "B": "Melville Bell"}, {"C": "reducing industry dependence on highly paid engineers.", "answer": "B", "question": "Henry L. Gantt\u2019s greatest achievement was", "status": "ok", "A": "founding Stevens Institute.", "D": "firing any inefficient worker.", "B": "the Gantt Chart."}, {"C": "Tesla", "answer": "E", "question": "In 1856 this person invented a process for converting iron into steel on a large scale:", "status": "ok", "A": "Swan", "E": "Bessemer.", "D": "Fisher", "B": "Argand"}, {"C": "The Sherman Anti-Trust Act", "answer": "B", "question": "In 1906 President T. Roosevelt signed into law", "status": "ok", "A": "The Marshall Plan for Economic Development", "D": "The Universal Voting Act", "B": "The Act of Preservation of Antiquities"}, {"C": "magnetos", "answer": "D", "question": "In 1913, Ford\u2019s assembly lines were producing:", "status": "ok", "A": "motors", "E": "none of the above", "D": "all of the above", "B": "transmissions"}, {"C": "four-dollar, 9-hour day", "answer": "E", "question": "In 1914, Henry Ford established the pay plan listed below, which more than doubled wages for a shorterwork day.", "status": "ok", "A": "three-dollar, 7-hour day", "E": "five-dollar, 8-hour day", "D": "eight-dollar, 7-hour day", "B": "four-dollar, 8-hour day"}, {"C": "color motion pictures", "answer": "A", "question": "In 1915, Peter L. Jensen and Edwin S. Pridham created what invention?", "status": "ok", "A": "the loudspeaker", "D": "synthetic rubber tires", "B": "the diesel engine"}, {"C": "Women are careful to stay detached from what they are studying and avoid the question of helping the object of study survive.", "answer": "A", "question": "In scientific endeavors, according to Barinaga and Lebacqz,", "status": "ok", "A": "Women have a capacity to empathize with the objects of their study.", "D": "Women publish more but what they publish is cited less.", "B": "Women focus more on scientific laws and less on individual subjects."}, {"C": "Women seek collaboration more than men.", "answer": "C", "question": "In scientific endeavors, according to Barinaga,", "status": "ok", "A": "Women are more competitive and design instruction that is more competitive.", "E": "Women are more focused on \u201chot\u201d topics than their male counterparts.", "D": "Women are less likely to listen to all sides of a question and seek compromise.", "B": "Women focus more on gaining recognition of their colleagues and less on results."}, {"C": "Midway", "answer": "D", "question": "In the 1880\u2019s, the Japanese government subsidized Mitsubishi, a private corporation, to build ships. As aresult, many people were forced to work in coal mines and live in terrible conditions on this island:", "status": "ok", "A": "Guam", "D": "Battleship.", "B": "Easter"}, {"C": "Department of Transportation", "answer": "E", "question": "In the 19th century this organization was given general federal responsibility for planning theconstructionof canals, making rivers navigible, and planning for flood control:", "status": "ok", "A": "Bureau of Reclaimation", "E": "Corps of Engineers.", "D": "U. S. Coast Guard", "B": "Rural Electrication Board"}, {"C": "fish and rice", "answer": "E", "question": "In the 19th century, this type of export provided the income Japan needed for modernization :", "status": "ok", "A": "electronics", "E": "silk.", "D": "cameras and optics", "B": "automobiles"}, {"C": "phonograph", "answer": "B", "question": "In the early part of this century, this invention or convenience dramatically changed traditional livingpatterns to give women access to the modern world.", "status": "ok", "A": "sewing machine", "E": "electric light.", "D": "newspaper", "B": "automobile"}, {"C": "to clean metal parts in industry", "answer": "B", "question": "In the late 1870\u2019s a less perishable dry gelatin emulsion was created. What was the gelatin used for?", "status": "ok", "A": "to make a household food item", "D": "to feed livestock", "B": "to develop photos"}, {"C": "color movie camera", "answer": "E", "question": "In the late 1930's, Chester Carlson endeavored to interest manufacturers in his:", "status": "ok", "A": "typewriter", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "molding machine", "B": "diesel engine"}, {"C": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "answer": "A", "question": "In the video America by Design: The House, who is credited with designing the first kitchen reflectingdomestic science?", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "D": "None of the above.", "B": "Thomas Jefferson"}, {"C": "1920-1929", "answer": "B", "question": "In which period did the first transatlantic flight occur?", "status": "ok", "A": "1900-1909", "D": "1930-1939", "B": "1910-1919"}, {"C": "St. Louis, MO", "answer": "A", "question": "Inspiration for the work of Ferdinand von Zeppelin\u2019s work with dirigibles came from an early flight he Atookover this city:", "status": "ok", "A": "St. Paul, MN", "E": "San Francisco, ", "D": "Denver, CO", "B": "Fargo, ND"}, {"C": "citizenship papers", "answer": "D", "question": "Jefferson believed that liberty would be threatened if individual families lacked:", "status": "ok", "A": "sufficient children", "E": "their own car.", "D": "private property", "B": "slaves"}, {"C": "improved phonograph", "answer": "B", "question": "Jensen and Pridham\u2019s original intent for their improved sound system was which of the following?", "status": "ok", "A": "radio speaker", "D": "sound motion pictures.", "B": "improved telephone receiver"}, {"C": "petroleum", "answer": "C", "question": "John D. Rockefeller made the majority of his fortune by investing in:", "status": "ok", "A": "steel", "D": "diamond mining", "B": "lumber"}, {"C": "they still will, ultimately, only be successful in traditional female roles.", "answer": "B", "question": "Karen Lebacqz believes that if women are given the opportunity,", "status": "ok", "A": "they can perform the same job function as any man.", "D": "they can offer the best contributions to society by following male role models and following the example of those women who have attained the highest level of success in today\u2019s world.", "B": "they can be successful in a culture that understands that a different style doesn\u2019t mean reduced ability."}, {"C": "the autobahn.", "answer": "B", "question": "Karl Benz is responsible for", "status": "ok", "A": "the invention of the automobile.", "D": "safety cages in automobiles.", "B": "making the automobile commercially feasible."}, {"C": "the assembly line.", "answer": "B", "question": "Kettering invented:", "status": "ok", "A": "rubber tires.", "D": "electric fuel injection.", "B": "self-starting automobile."}, {"C": "In manufacturing.", "answer": "A", "question": "Kostof referred to a different kind of organized labor as occurring:", "status": "ok", "A": "In agriculture.", "D": "In communism.", "B": "In steel."}, {"C": "Wright as an architect and Edison as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "answer": "B", "question": "Kostoff sees Ford as owing a debt to:", "status": "ok", "A": "Taylor for his skill as an architect and Kahn as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Kahn for his skill as an architect and Gantt as a contributor toward efficient use of labor.", "B": "Kahn for his skill as an architect and Taylor as a contributor toward efficient use of labor."}, {"C": "About himself and the Spirit of St. Louis", "answer": "C", "question": "Lindbergh\u2019s book We was:", "status": "ok", "A": "\u201cGhost-written\u201d by his first wife.", "E": "Never published until after his death.", "D": "About his partnership with Goddard", "B": "About his wife and murdered son."}, {"C": "pilot in Byrd\u2019s arctic exhibition", "answer": "A", "question": "Lindbergh\u2019s first job was as a(n):", "status": "ok", "A": "wing-stunter", "E": "clerk in his father\u2019s aviation business.", "D": "mechanic for Edison", "B": "air mail pilot"}, {"C": "We must all dance like the Dancing Cabinet.", "answer": "A", "question": "Meiji rule created a new political perspective in Japan which was described as:", "status": "ok", "A": "Heaven creates no man above or below another.", "E": "Korea must be annexed!", "D": "Rich Nation, Stong Emperor.", "B": "No Japanese has any rights at all."}, {"C": "considers the plight of the assembly line worker and the working poor.", "answer": "C", "question": "Modern Times:", "status": "ok", "A": "was Chaplin\u2019s first silent film.", "D": "was the first appearance of Chaplin\u2019s \u201cLittle Tramp\u201d character.", "B": "was Buster Keaton\u2019s last film."}, {"C": "1874 with the Remington typewriter.", "answer": "C", "question": "Office mechanization began in:", "status": "ok", "A": "1898 with the Poulsen typewriter.", "E": "1898 with the Remington typewriter.", "D": "1874 with the Burroughs typewriter", "B": "1925 with the IBM typewriter."}, {"C": "to reunite the country with China", "answer": "D", "question": "One hundred years ago there was a people\u2019s movement in Japan:", "status": "ok", "A": "to restore the emperor as a god", "D": "to establish a modern democratic constitution.", "B": "to return to the cultural values of the past"}, {"C": "construction", "answer": "D", "question": "Peter Jensen\u2019s career was in the field of:", "status": "ok", "A": "cars", "D": "radio engineering", "B": "medical treatment"}, {"C": "Charles Pfeifer", "answer": "B", "question": "Peter L. Jensen became \u201cinseparable friends\u201d with", "status": "ok", "A": "Valdemar Poulsen", "E": "Rudi Blesh.", "D": "George Grinnell", "B": "Edwin S. Pridham"}, {"C": "Efficiency Movement", "answer": "D", "question": "Pinchot was the architect of the:", "status": "ok", "A": "Progressive Movement", "D": "Conservation Movement", "B": "Scientific Movement"}, {"C": "Near Detroit.", "answer": "D", "question": "Pullman\u2019s company city was/is located:", "status": "ok", "A": "In Washington, now the site of Washington State University.", "D": "Near Chicago.", "B": "Near Lowell, Mass."}, {"C": "sometimes are spontaneous answers giving information from the point of view of everyday human experience.", "answer": "E", "question": "Rogers argued that foolish answers by the public to questions about astronomy:", "status": "ok", "A": "demonstrates the decline of the ability of teachers in public schools.", "E": "B, C, and D above.", "D": "may be correlated with the fact that some scientific answers, though correct, only partially deal with the subject.", "B": "shows a diminished interest in science on the part of the public."}, {"C": "Susan Wright", "answer": "D", "question": "She became a writer, navigator, and radio operator when she married a Minnesota Congressman\u2019s son:", "status": "ok", "A": "Amelia Earhart", "E": "Harriet Quimby.", "D": "Anne Murrow", "B": "Catherine Beecher"}, {"C": "modern times put a high price on loneliness.", "answer": "D", "question": "Soseki claims that:", "status": "ok", "A": "modern times are the result of the loneliness experienced by great inventors.", "E": "he would pay any price for the benefits of living in modern times.", "D": "loneliness is the price you pay for living in modern times.", "B": "loneliness is the price you pay for leaving rural life behind."}, {"C": "his Nobel Prize for Peace", "answer": "C", "question": "T. Roosevelt\u2019s involvement in the Russo-Japanese War immediately led to:", "status": "ok", "A": "the bombing of Pearl Harbor", "E": "World War I.", "D": "the Battle of the Sea of Japan involving the Great White Navy", "B": "the democratization of Korea"}, {"C": "Devised by Thomas Edison in the 1840's.", "answer": "E", "question": "The \"QWERTY\" keyboard was:", "status": "ok", "A": "Devised by Christopher Scholes in the 1920's.", "E": "Devised by Christopher Scholes in the 1870's.", "D": "Devised by Christopher Robin in the 1920's.", "B": "Devised by Eliphalet Remington in the 1920's."}, {"C": "the name of Harriet Beecher Stowe\u2019s childhood home", "answer": "D", "question": "The \u201cPrairie House\u201d was:", "status": "ok", "A": "the title of a book about modern kitchens by Catherine Beecher", "E": "a style of home that originated with Aca Packer.", "D": "a style of home that originated with Frank Lloyd Wright", "B": "what early pioneers called their covered wagons"}, {"C": "Thomas Edison", "answer": "A", "question": "The Aerial Experiment Association was by a group of engineers including Glenn Curtiss along withinventor", "status": "ok", "A": "A. G. Bell", "E": "Valdemar Poulsen", "D": "Alexander M. Poniatoff", "B": "O. Wright"}, {"C": "movie camera", "answer": "B", "question": "The Brazilian Emperor Dom Pedro II saw a demonstration of this invention at the Centennial Exhibition:", "status": "ok", "A": "airplane", "E": "roll film.", "D": "public address system", "B": "telephone"}, {"C": "17", "answer": "C", "question": "The constitution provided for a patent system, and, by law, the inventor was granted a legal monopoly fora period of how many years?", "status": "ok", "A": "7", "D": "37", "B": "27"}, {"C": "breakdown movements into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary work.", "answer": "A", "question": "The couple that inspired the movie Cheaper by the Dozen worked on improving worker efficiencythrough the approach described as follows:", "status": "ok", "A": "breakdown work into basic motion and to eliminate unnecessary movements.", "D": "breakdown work into basic traditional and rotational motions.", "B": "breakdown motion into basic movements and to eliminate unnecessary motion."}, {"C": "the defeat of Spain in the Spanish-American War.", "answer": "D", "question": "The culmination of Meiji's transformation of Japan was:", "status": "ok", "A": "the building of the Tokyo Railroad.", "E": "the invention of the transistor by Japanese scientists.", "D": "the defeat of Russia in the Russo-Japanese War.", "B": "the adoption of the Prussian Constitution for Japanese use."}, {"C": "The decade when small was beautiful", "answer": "B", "question": "The decade of the 1920\u2019s was known by some to be the:", "status": "ok", "A": "The Age of New Leadership", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "The Decade of the Great Awakening", "B": "The Age of Small Men"}, {"C": "Korea", "answer": "E", "question": "The decline of this Asian nation pushed Japan in the direction of modernization:", "status": "ok", "A": "Angola", "E": "China.", "D": "Russia", "B": "Vietnam"}, {"C": "Marconi", "answer": "D", "question": "The dial telephone was invented in the United States by:", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "E": "Poulsen", "D": "Strowger", "B": "Bell"}, {"C": "50 years", "answer": "C", "question": "The electric light had been worked on for about how many years before Edison began his experiments:", "status": "ok", "A": "10 years", "E": "200 years.", "D": "100 years", "B": "20 years"}, {"C": "Southern Europe", "answer": "C", "question": "The first electric battery originated in this area around 200 years ago:", "status": "ok", "A": "Far East", "E": "New England.", "D": "Australia", "B": "Northern Europe"}, {"C": "RCA Victor", "answer": "E", "question": "The first experiments with sound recording on plastic tape were done by:", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison\u2019s East Coast laboratory", "E": "Magnetophone.", "D": "3M", "B": "Magnavox"}, {"C": "France in 1912", "answer": "E", "question": "The first successful European demonstration of a Wright plane occurred in:", "status": "ok", "A": "Germany in 1908", "E": "France in 1908.", "D": "London in 1906", "B": "Germany in 1912"}, {"C": "Elmer Sperry", "answer": "D", "question": "The first triple-arched bridge across the Mississippi River at Saint Louis was designed by whom?", "status": "ok", "A": "Thomas Thorton", "D": "James Ead", "B": "Harris Ryan"}, {"C": "Completed in the 1930\u2019s through local financing.", "answer": "C", "question": "The Golden Gate bridge was:", "status": "ok", "A": "Completed in the 1930\u2019s through Federal financing.", "E": "Was rebuilt in the 1940\u2019s after being destroyed in a storm", "D": "Completed in the 1920\u2019s through a Federal-State partnership.", "B": "Completed in the 1920\u2019s through Federal financing."}, {"C": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name Westinghouse Co.", "answer": "B", "question": "The invention of the electric chair led to:", "status": "ok", "A": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name General Motors Co.", "E": "Increased positive publicity for the inventor\u2019s research laboratory and increased funding.", "D": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name Business Machines Co.", "B": "Removal of the inventor\u2019s name from the company name leading to the name General Electric Co."}, {"C": "1929-1931.", "answer": "B", "question": "The last model T came off the assembly line in the period:", "status": "ok", "A": "1923-1925.", "E": "1935-1937.", "D": "1932-1934.", "B": "1926-1928."}, {"C": "Chrysler", "answer": "B", "question": "The last of the three major automobile manufacturers to sign with the United Auto Workers after thedepression of the 1930\u2019s was:", "status": "ok", "A": "General Motors", "E": "Nissan", "D": "American Motors", "B": "Ford"}, {"C": "Bismarck", "answer": "C", "question": "The Meiji political planners modeled their government after that of which world leader of the time?", "status": "ok", "A": "T. Roosevelt", "E": "Ho Chi Minh", "D": "Gladstone", "B": "Napolean"}, {"C": "a movie that caused mass hysteria when it was first shown in New York", "answer": "D", "question": "The Mercury Theater was:", "status": "ok", "A": "a New York theater where the planetarium was invented", "E": "the location of a bloody World War II battle.", "D": "a program in which Orson Welles was heavily involved.", "B": "a theater in Utah where the idea of unidentified flying objects was first developed"}, {"C": "had higher ratio of horsepower to weight.", "answer": "D", "question": "The Model T, compared to the European touring car:", "status": "ok", "A": "was lower priced.", "E": "none of the above.", "D": "all of the above.", "B": "was much lighter."}, {"C": "Grand Coulee Dam", "answer": "B", "question": "The oldest surviving Ampex black and white videotape depicts:", "status": "ok", "A": "Golden Gate Bridge", "E": "English Channel Tunnel", "D": "Santa Barbara beaches", "B": "Hoover Dam"}, {"C": "Grand Coulee Dam", "answer": "E", "question": "The oldest surviving color videotape depicts the:", "status": "ok", "A": "Golden Gate Bridge", "E": "Nixon-Khruschev encounter.", "D": "Kennedy-Nixon debates", "B": "Hoover Dam"}, {"C": "J. D. Rockefellar, Sr.", "answer": "B", "question": "The phrase \u201cThe man who dies rich dies in disgrace\u201d is attributed to:", "status": "ok", "A": "J. P. Morgan", "E": "Steve Wozniak", "D": "Bill Gates", "B": "A. Carnegie"}, {"C": "Korea", "answer": "C", "question": "The Portsmouth Treaty made this nation a vessel state of Japan:", "status": "ok", "A": "Angola", "E": "China.", "D": "Russia", "B": "Vietnam"}, {"C": "RCA Victor", "answer": "E", "question": "The ring-shaped recording head with a gap to concentrate the magnetic field was invented by:", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison\u2019s East Coast laboratory", "E": "Magnetophone.", "D": "3M", "B": "Magnavox"}, {"C": "1850-1859", "answer": "D", "question": "The Shogun's Army was defeated near Kyoto during this period. This was a major event in the inthe history of the modernization of Japan.", "status": "ok", "A": "1830-1839", "E": "1870-1879", "D": "1860-1869", "B": "1840-1849"}, {"C": "The gift of a toy helicopter when they were young.", "answer": "C", "question": "The Wright brothers interest in flying was sparked by:", "status": "ok", "A": "Susan\u2019s early interest in hot air ballooning (invented in France a century earlier).", "E": "Their desire to compete for the $25,000 prize offered for a successful flight from New York to Paris.", "D": "Rebellion against a father who allowed them to have no interests outside of church and school.", "B": "Catherine\u2019s early interest in hot air ballooning (invented in France a century earlier)."}, {"C": "350 feet in 39 seconds.", "answer": "A", "question": "The Wright\u2019s fourth successful flight on December 17, 1903 was:", "status": "ok", "A": "850 feet in 59 seconds.", "E": "None of the above. It happened in 1906.", "D": "None of the above. It happened in 1900.", "B": "85 feet in 6 seconds."}, {"C": "1961-1965", "answer": "B", "question": "The Xerox 914 was first available to the public in:", "status": "ok", "A": "1951-1955", "E": "1971-1975", "D": "1966-1970", "B": "1956-1960"}, {"C": "George Pullman", "answer": "B", "question": "This American industrialist was a strong supporter of a World War I peace movement:", "status": "ok", "A": "Andrew Carnegie", "E": "James Buchanan Eads", "D": "Charles I. du Pont", "B": "Henry Ford"}, {"C": "Charles Lindbergh", "answer": "C", "question": "This aviator was a very prominent spokesman for the American First movement:", "status": "ok", "A": "Wilbur Wright", "E": "Wiley Post", "D": "Glen Curtis", "B": "Samuel Langley"}, {"C": "Samuel Langlie", "answer": "E", "question": "This collaborator with Alexander Graham Bell was the first person killed in a powered airplane accident:", "status": "ok", "A": "John Daniels", "E": "T.E. Selfridge", "D": "A. Santos-Dumont", "B": "Glen Curtis"}, {"C": "Edison General Electric", "answer": "B", "question": "This company turned down a chance to buy the rights to the telephone in 1876:", "status": "ok", "A": "Westinghouse", "E": "Sony", "D": "General Electric", "B": "Western Union"}, {"C": "E. Fermi", "answer": "B", "question": "This famous person served some of the medical needs of soldiers during World War I:", "status": "ok", "A": "A. Einstein", "E": "C. Wright", "D": "L. Szilard", "B": "M. Curie"}, {"C": "Lindbergh", "answer": "C", "question": "This individual was well known for never doubting his own abilities and holding to the certainties of hisown opinions:", "status": "ok", "A": "Whitney", "E": "Francis", "D": "Kreusi", "B": "Edison"}, {"C": "Gantt and Barth", "answer": "D", "question": "This nineteenth century engineer/designer team developed machine tools capable of producing largenumbers of pulley blocks for the British Navy:", "status": "ok", "A": "Eckert and Mauchly", "E": "McCormick and Whitney", "D": "Brunel and Maudsley", "B": "Taylor and Gilbreth"}, {"C": "John L. Lewis", "answer": "A", "question": "This person criticized America in the 1930\u2019s for buying gas before buying food:", "status": "ok", "A": "John Steinbeck", "E": "Will Durant.", "D": "Walter Reuther", "B": "Sinclair Lewis"}, {"C": "Jack Benny", "answer": "D", "question": "This person made major contributions in establishing the audio and video recording industry in the United States:", "status": "ok", "A": "Charles Scholes", "E": "Arthur M. Pedrick.", "D": "Alexander M. Poniatoff", "B": "William C. Durant"}, {"C": "Ellen Swallow Richards", "answer": "A", "question": "This person roots her understanding of the work of women in science as paralleling the concept ofempathyas understood from moral development theory.", "status": "ok", "A": "Karen Lebacqz", "E": "Eleanor Roosevelt.", "D": "Anne Murrow Lindbergh", "B": "Catherine Wright"}, {"C": "Ellen S. Richards", "answer": "A", "question": "This poet later became an aviation pioneer:", "status": "ok", "A": "A. M. Lindbergh", "E": "Christina Dumont", "D": "Catherine Beecher", "B": "Susan Isaac"}, {"C": "American Automobile Association", "answer": "D", "question": "This powerful manufacturing group engaged in a patent dispute with Henry Ford:", "status": "ok", "A": "Gas Auto Association", "E": "North American Registered Automobile Manufacturers.", "D": "Association of Licensed Automobile Manufacturers", "B": "National Association of Manufacturers"}, {"C": "Vanderbilt", "answer": "D", "question": "This son of a poor weaver became a giant in the steel industry and donated over 7,000 pipe organs andbuilt over 3,000 public libraries:", "status": "ok", "A": "Rockefeller", "D": "Carnegie", "B": "Morgan"}, {"C": "Menlo Park, New Jersey", "answer": "C", "question": "Thomas Alva Edison\u2019s main laboratory was located where?", "status": "ok", "A": "Nestor, Massachusetts", "D": "Menlo Park, California", "B": "Springfield, Illinois"}, {"C": "every family should own a home and their own plot of land.", "answer": "C", "question": "Thomas Jefferson believed:", "status": "ok", "A": "each and every family in America should have the same income.", "D": "every family should not have children.", "B": "every family should have slaves."}, {"C": "Optics", "answer": "D", "question": "To which science(s) did the Greeks make notable contributions:", "status": "ok", "A": "Acoustics", "E": "A and C only", "D": "All of the above", "B": "Astronomy"}, {"C": "Can I make a profit from it?", "answer": "A", "question": "Traditionally, a scientist\u2019s principal concern is:", "status": "ok", "A": "Is it true?", "E": "A and C only.", "D": "B and C only.", "B": "Will it work?"}, {"C": "to record a politician\u2019s campaign promises.", "answer": "A", "question": "Valdemar Poulsen envisioned magnetic recording as mainly useful:", "status": "ok", "A": "to record business transactions.", "E": "to record the secret conversations of government officials.", "D": "to record popular songs magnetically instead of mechanically.", "B": "to record a dying person\u2019s will."}, {"C": "telephone", "answer": "B", "question": "Valdemar Poulsen won a grand prize at the Paris Universal Exhibition of 1900 for a device called the\u201cTelegraphone,\u201d an early forerunner of the:", "status": "ok", "A": "telegraph", "D": "record player", "B": "tape recorder"}, {"C": "Very Early Recording Apparatus (Edison's photoelectric recording system)", "answer": "A", "question": "VERA was the abbreviation used for:", "status": "ok", "A": "BBC's Vision Electronics Recording Apparatus.", "E": "GE's Vision Electronics Recording Apparatus.", "D": "NBC Vision Electronic Recording Apparatus.", "B": "the Ampex system of video recording"}, {"C": "Irrigation", "answer": "A", "question": "Water used in the recent past neglected this use of water:", "status": "ok", "A": "Habitat", "E": "Recreation", "D": "Hydroelectric power", "B": "Drinking and sanitation"}, {"C": "science", "answer": "B", "question": "What did Karen Lebacqz refer to as a social constructed category?", "status": "ok", "A": "race", "D": "technology", "B": "gender"}, {"C": "long-term influences of scientific research were captured by industry.", "answer": "A", "question": "What did the authors of the study on the Queen\u2019s Award for Industry conclude:", "status": "ok", "A": "the great bulk of basic science bears only tenuously if at all on the operations of industry.", "D": "little is known about the influence of science on industry.", "B": "basic research seems to be significant as a direct source of innovations."}, {"C": "Wall Street", "answer": "C", "question": "What famous New York City Street was Edison\u2019s choice for his first use of artificial lights?", "status": "ok", "A": "Broadway", "D": "42nd Street", "B": "5th Avenue"}, {"C": "vacuum jacket", "answer": "B", "question": "What Fleming device was commercially used for the detection of radio signals?", "status": "ok", "A": "storage battery", "D": "outward-flow turbine", "B": "oscillation valve"}, {"C": "photography", "answer": "B", "question": "What invention made George Eastman famous?", "status": "ok", "A": "glass-plate photography", "D": "radiotelegraphy", "B": "roll film camera with 100 exposures"}, {"C": "small business.", "answer": "A", "question": "What type of employment did the Industrial Revolution largely displace?", "status": "ok", "A": "work in the home.", "D": "manufacturing.", "B": "door-to-door sales."}, {"C": "being orderly.", "answer": "C", "question": "What was Frederick Winslow Taylor\u2019s obsession?", "status": "ok", "A": "cleanliness.", "D": "money.", "B": "soccer."}, {"C": "The Bonus Army\u2019s march on Washington.", "answer": "B", "question": "What was the great event that brought a halt to production and curtailed use of the passenger car?", "status": "ok", "A": "Atomic bomb development drained the country of financial resources.", "E": "Increased train travel in the early 1920\u2019s.", "D": "The Great Upheaval", "B": "World War II"}, {"C": "World War II", "answer": "C", "question": "What was the great event that brought a halt to production and curtailed use of the passenger car?", "status": "ok", "A": "The Great Depression", "D": "The Dust Bowl", "B": "World War I"}, {"C": "pull train cars.", "answer": "A", "question": "What was the initial use of the steam engine?", "status": "ok", "A": "pump water out of mines.", "D": "power the reaper.", "B": "propel a boat."}, {"C": "A strike", "answer": "A", "question": "When workers would deliberately limit their production to what they thought was fair, it involved what iscalled:", "status": "ok", "A": "A stint", "D": "Justice", "B": "Selfishness"}, {"C": "The loss of teeth in hockey and the death of his mother.", "answer": "C", "question": "Which event(s) led to Wilbur Wright\u2019s long battle with depression?", "status": "ok", "A": "The crash of their airplane in early 1903.", "E": "The marriage of his sister Catherine.", "D": "His horseback riding accident and the death of his father in the same year.", "B": "The death of his father when his was 18 years old"}, {"C": "Ellen Swallow Richards", "answer": "D", "question": "Which great woman of the 20th century authored North to the Orient and Listen! The Wind?", "status": "ok", "A": "Karen Lebacqz", "E": "Eleanor Roosevelt.", "D": "Anne Murrow Lindbergh", "B": "Catherine Wright"}, {"C": "automobile", "answer": "B", "question": "Which industry was on such a tight schedule the workers were required to have \u201cgood\u201d watches?", "status": "ok", "A": "steel", "D": "telephone", "B": "railroad"}, {"C": "telephone", "answer": "D", "question": "Which item did Alexander Graham Bell not invent?", "status": "ok", "A": "probe that could locate bullets in a body", "D": "telegraph", "B": "\u201cvacuum jacket\u201d"}, {"C": "phonograph", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following did Edison (with Kreusi) invent?", "status": "ok", "A": "telegraph", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "A and C", "B": "automobile"}, {"C": "She was the first appointed female instructor-in sanitary chemistry and assistant in the laboratory for the chemical study of sanitation at MIT.", "answer": "E", "question": "Which of the following statements is true about Ellen Swallow Richards?", "status": "ok", "A": "She was the first woman to attend Massachusetts Institute of Technology.", "E": "All of the above.", "D": "She campaigned to have domestic science included in the curriculum of the Boston high schools.", "B": "She was born in 1842 in a small New England village."}, {"C": "Fishing", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following was not a major theme of the water conservation movement?", "status": "ok", "A": "Irrigation", "D": "Hydroelectric power", "B": "Navigation"}, {"C": "Henry Ford and son Edsel", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the two men were credited with building the first successful American gasoline-powered car in1893?", "status": "ok", "A": "Emill Constant Levassor and Karl Benz", "D": "William C. Durant and Reynold M. Wik", "B": "Charles E. and J. Frank Duryea"}, {"C": "She was a founder of sanitary engineering.", "answer": "E", "question": "Which of these statements about Ellen Swallow Richards is not true?", "status": "ok", "A": "She was MIT\u2019s first female instructor.", "E": "She worked hard to oppose the domestic science movement.", "D": "She wrote correspondence courses.", "B": "She had a stable marriage."}, {"C": "Gifford Pinchot", "answer": "C", "question": "Which one of the following is usually identified with the \u201cconservation movement\u201d of the early 1900\u2019s?", "status": "ok", "A": "Frederick Winslow Taylor", "D": "Ellen Swallow Richards", "B": "Peter L. Jensen"}, {"C": "Samuel Howd", "answer": "D", "question": "Who assumed the presidency of the National Geographic Society in 1897 on the death of GardinerHubbard? This person is also responsible for the popularity of the National Geographic Magazine.", "status": "ok", "A": "Charles Pfeifer", "D": "Alexander Graham Bell", "B": "Uriah A. Boyden"}, {"C": "Okata", "answer": "D", "question": "Who became the first prime minister of Japan during the Meiji revolution?", "status": "ok", "A": "Sakomoyo", "E": "None of the above", "D": "Ito", "B": "Meiji"}, {"C": "Durant", "answer": "D", "question": "Who created a system of greater industrial efficiency, called Scientific Management?", "status": "ok", "A": "Carnegie", "D": "Taylor", "B": "Ford"}, {"C": "Gardiner Greene Hubbard", "answer": "D", "question": "Who filed a \u201cstatement of conception\u201d for a telephone device only hours after Alexander Graham Belldid?", "status": "ok", "A": "Samuel F.B. Morse", "D": "Elisha Gray", "B": "Samuel Langley"}, {"C": "Galbraith", "answer": "B", "question": "Who founded General Motors?", "status": "ok", "A": "Ford", "D": "Taylor", "B": "Durant"}, {"C": "Rogers", "answer": "A", "question": "Who is reputed to have said that he could see farther because he stood on the shoulders of giants?", "status": "ok", "A": "Newton", "D": "Aiken", "B": "Carlson"}, {"C": "Thomas Alva Edison", "answer": "C", "question": "Who rates as one of the most prolific American inventors and was called the American Hero of theGilded Age?", "status": "ok", "A": "Eli Whitney", "D": "Thomas Jefferson", "B": "Edgar Allan Poe"}, {"C": "Henry Gantt", "answer": "D", "question": "Who took Taylorism to the U.S. Federal Arsenal in Watertown in 1909?", "status": "ok", "A": "Frederick Taylor", "D": "Carl Barth", "B": "Frank Gilbreth"}, {"C": "Henry Davidson", "answer": "A", "question": "Who was Karl Marx\u2019s collaborator and a strong advocate of the rights of working people?", "status": "ok", "A": "Fredrick Engels", "D": "Stephen A. Burke", "B": "Cary Wolinsky"}, {"C": "Browne", "answer": "D", "question": "Who was nicknamed \u201cThe Flying Fool?\u201d", "status": "ok", "A": "Byrd", "D": "Lindbergh", "B": "Chamberlin"}, {"C": "Susan Nichols", "answer": "B", "question": "Who was one of the founders of the discipline of sanitary engineering in the United States and was alsoamong the first women in the U.S. to be formally employed as a scientist?", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "D": "Lillian Gilbreth", "B": "Ellen Richards"}, {"C": "Daniel Guggenheim", "answer": "B", "question": "Who was said to have opened a new \u201cfrontier\u201d with his famous airplane flight which represented anadvance into a complex industrial present?", "status": "ok", "A": "Robert Godderd", "D": "H.G. Wells", "B": "Charles Lindbergh"}, {"C": "Garfield", "answer": "D", "question": "Who was the first professionally trained forester in the U.S.?", "status": "ok", "A": "Roosevelt", "D": "Pinchot", "B": "Douglas"}, {"C": "Bell", "answer": "C", "question": "Who was the man who was concerned with communication and breaking down the barriers betweenpeople because both his mother and wife were deaf?", "status": "ok", "A": "Edison", "D": "Jensen", "B": "Eastman"}, {"C": "Ellen Richards", "answer": "C", "question": "Who was the woman responsible for starting the American Home Economics Association?", "status": "ok", "A": "Catherine Beecher", "D": "Kate Smith", "B": "Helen Hayes"}, {"C": "Keaton & Laborde", "answer": "D", "question": "Who were the greatest silent film comedians?", "status": "ok", "A": "Laborde & Rutherford", "D": "Chaplin & Keaton", "B": "Chaplin & Rutherford"}, {"C": "Upton Sinclair", "answer": "C", "question": "Who wrote the famous book The Jungle?", "status": "ok", "A": "George Gastman", "D": "Gifford Pinchot", "B": "Ellen Richards"}, {"C": "They wanted a say in the new government.", "answer": "D", "question": "Why did the farmers of Japan work so hard to pay high taxes without complaining during themodernization of Japan?", "status": "ok", "A": "They owned their own land.", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "All of the above.", "B": "Their children would benefit from their efforts."}, {"C": "Hook", "answer": "D", "question": "With the help of whom did Alexander Graham Bell develop the diaphragm used in the telephone?", "status": "ok", "A": "John Bell", "D": "Watson", "B": "Swan"}, {"C": "Long live the Emperor!", "answer": "B", "question": "With the Meiji transformation of Japan, there was an short era of confusion that swept Japan. It wasknowby the phrase Eijaniaka, which meant:", "status": "ok", "A": "Hippies all!", "E": "None of the above.", "D": "Drive out the barbarians!", "B": "Who cares!"}]
